<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<pr:sect2 xmlns:pr="http://qld.gov.au/profiles">
    <pr:title>Standard Conformance</pr:title>
    <pr:para>Conformance to the standard is defined by adherence to the set of requirements defined
        for a specific target, within the scope of the standard. This section explains these terms
        and describes how conformance is defined and used.</pr:para>

    <pr:sect3>
        <pr:title>Conformance Levels</pr:title>
        <pr:para>This Standard defines three conformance levels to describe Web Services
            implementations’ conformance compliance to the Standard:</pr:para>
        <pr:unordered_list>

            <pr:item xml:space="preserve">
                    <pr:conformance-level>NON CONFORMANT</pr:conformance-level> - An implementation
                    is said to be <pr:conformance-level>NON CONFORMANT</pr:conformance-level> if it fails to
                    satisfy one or more of the <pr:rfc2119-keyword>MUST</pr:rfc2119-keyword> or
                    <pr:rfc2119-keyword>REQUIRED</pr:rfc2119-keyword> level requirements for the artifacts
                    it exposes.</pr:item>

            <pr:item xml:space="preserve">
                    <pr:conformance-level>CONDITIONALLY CONFORMANT</pr:conformance-level> – An
                    implementation that satisfies all the <pr:rfc2119-keyword>MUST</pr:rfc2119-keyword>
                    level requirements but not all the <pr:rfc2119-keyword>SHOULD</pr:rfc2119-keyword> or
                    <pr:rfc2119-keyword>REQUIRED</pr:rfc2119-keyword> level requirements is said to be
                    <pr:conformance-level>CONDITIONALLY CONFORMANT</pr:conformance-level>.</pr:item>

            <pr:item xml:space="preserve">
                    <pr:conformance-level>UNCONDITIONALLY CONFORMANT</pr:conformance-level> – An
                    implementation that satisfies all the <pr:rfc2119-keyword>MUST NOT</pr:rfc2119-keyword>
                    or <pr:rfc2119-keyword>REQUIRED</pr:rfc2119-keyword> level and all the
                    <pr:rfc2119-keyword>SHOULD</pr:rfc2119-keyword> or
                    <pr:rfc2119-keyword>RECOMMENDED</pr:rfc2119-keyword> level requirements is said to be
                    <pr:conformance-level>UNCONDITIONALLY CONFORMANT</pr:conformance-level>.</pr:item>
        </pr:unordered_list>
    </pr:sect3>

    <pr:sect3>
        <pr:title>Conformance requirements</pr:title>

        <pr:para>Requirements state the criteria for conformance to the Standard. They occasionally
            refer to an existing specification or profile of standards (such as WS-I) and embody
            refinements, interpretations and clarifications to it in order to improve
            interoperability. All requirements in the standard are considered normative unless
            otherwise clearly defined as being non-normative, and are testable where possible. When
            requirements in the standard and its referenced specifications contradict each other,
            the standard requirements take precedence for purposes of conformance. Requirement
            levels, using RFC2119 terminology (e.g., <pr:rfc2119-keyword>MUST</pr:rfc2119-keyword>,
                <pr:rfc2119-keyword>SHOULD</pr:rfc2119-keyword>,
            <pr:rfc2119-keyword>MAY</pr:rfc2119-keyword>) indicate the nature of the requirement and
            its impact on conformance. Each requirement is individually identified (e.g., GEAXXXX)
            for convenience. For example: GEAXXXX WIDGETs
            <pr:rfc2119-keyword>SHOULD</pr:rfc2119-keyword> be round in shape. This requirement is
            identified by GEAXXXX, applies to the conformance target WIDGET, and places a
            conditional requirement upon widgets; i.e., although this requirement must be met to
            maintain conformance in majority of cases, situations may exist where there may be valid
            reasons for it not being met (which are explained in the requirement itself, or in its
            accompanying text). Each requirement statement contains one or more non-contradicting
            requirement level constructs (e.g., "<pr:rfc2119-keyword>MUST</pr:rfc2119-keyword>",
                “<pr:rfc2119-keyword>REQUIRED</pr:rfc2119-keyword>”) and one or more conformance
            target keywords (e.g., "MESSAGE" or “DESCRIPTION”). Additional text may be included to
            illuminate a requirement or group of requirements (e.g., rationale and examples);
            however, prose surrounding requirement statements must not be considered in determining
            conformance. Definitions of terms in the standard are considered authoritative for the
            purposes of determining conformance.</pr:para>
    </pr:sect3>

</pr:sect2>
