<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!--Sample XML file generated by XMLSpy v2010 rel. 3 (x64) (http://www.altova.com)-->
<wfs:FeatureCollection xsi:schemaLocation='http://stategeothermaldata.org/uri-gin/aasg/xmlschema/activefault/1.1 http://schemas.usgin.org/schemas/ActiveFault1.1.xsd  
http://www.opengis.net/wfs http://schemas.opengis.net/wfs/1.1.0/wfs.xsd' xmlns:aasg='http://stategeothermaldata.org/uri-gin/aasg/xmlschema/activefault/1.1' xmlns:gml='http://www.opengis.net/gml' xmlns:wfs='http://www.opengis.net/wfs' xmlns:xsi='http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance'>
	<!-- GeoSciML portrayal view shear displacement structure example, for Algodones fault -->
	<!-- SMR 20110923, based on AASG stateGeothermalData Active Fault (http://stategeothermaldata.org/uri-gin/aasg/xmlschema/activefault/1.1, schema location
http://schemas.usgin.org/schemas/ActiveFault1.1.xsd -->
	<gml:boundedBy>
		<gml:Envelope srsName='urn:ogc:def:crs:EPSG:6.9:26912'>
			<gml:lowerCorner>161124.06190000009 3359253.5865000002</gml:lowerCorner>
			<gml:upperCorner>685354.02350000013 4099117.7627000008</gml:upperCorner>
		</gml:Envelope>
	</gml:boundedBy>
	<gml:featureMember>
		<gsmlp:ShearDisplacementStructureView gml:id="testFaults264436" xsi:schemaLocation="http://xmlns.geosciml.org/geosciml-portrayal/1.0 http://www.geosciml.org/schemas/geosciml-portrayal/1.0/geosciml-portrayal.xsd " xmlns:gsmlp="http://xmlns.geosciml.org/geosciml-portrayal/1.0">
			<gml:boundedBy>
				<gml:Envelope srsName='urn:ogc:def:crs:EPSG:6.9:26912'>
					<gml:lowerCorner>161124.06190000009 3359253.5865000002</gml:lowerCorner>
					<gml:upperCorner>685354.02350000013 4099117.7627000008</gml:upperCorner>
				</gml:Envelope>
			</gml:boundedBy>
			<gsmlp:identifier>http://resources.usgin.org/uri-gin/azgs/fault/QAF.ContactsAndFaults.1/</gsmlp:identifier>
			<gsmlp:name>Algodones fault</gsmlp:name>
			<gsmlp:description>Description: The Algodones fault zone consists of northwest-trending predominantly normal faults located within the Yuma Desert, southeast of Yuma, on the margin of the San Andreas fault system (California).  The Yuma Desert, which is a broad plain between the Gila Mountains and the lowermost Colorado River, is covered with locally-derived alluvium, deposits of the Colorado River, and eolian deposits.  The Algodones fault zone follows a basement high located between two deep late Cenozoic basins.  Its faults displace probable upper Pleistocene Colorado River deposits on Upper Mesa by at least 15 m.  Trenches revealed a broad zone of faults that dip northeast and have predominantly normal displacement.  Multiple buried soil horizons and colluvial wedges are displaced by faulting, indicating that multiple events occurred in the late Pleistocene.  The amount of vertical displacement per event is estimated at 0.5-1.5 m.  Holocene eolian deposits blanket the faults and are not displaced. The age of youngest displacement was estimated to be latest Pleistocene (11-15 ka).  Geomorphic Expression: Faulting is expressed as 7- to 15-m-high, northeast-facing scarps formed on Upper Mesa, a Pleistocene terrace of the Colorado River.  The scarp is well-defined on topographic maps and on aerial photographs.  No morphologic data has been reported for this scarp.  Geologic Setting: The Algodones fault zone is composed of northwest-trending predominantly normal faults located northeast of the main San Andreas transform fault system.  The Algodones fault zone is within the Yuma Desert, a broad plain between the Gila Mountains and the lowermost Colorado River. The Algodones fault zone follows a basement high between the deep (ca. 2000 m), fairly narrow late Cenozoic Fortuna basin to the northeast and the deep (greater than 2000 m), broader San Luis basin to the southwest (Mattick and others, 1973).  The Algodones faults displace probable upper Pleistocene Colorado River deposits on Upper Mesa by at least 15 m (Woodward-McNeil and Associates, 1974).  Sense of Movement Comments: Some workers have inferred right-lateral strike-slip displacement based primarily on fault orientation relative to the nearby faults of the San Andreas system.  The Algodones fault zone was even considered as a possible continuation of the San  Dip Direction Comments: Dip directions are based on faults mapped in trench logs trenches (Woodward-McNeil &amp; Associates, 1974).  Timing Comments: Trenching studies indicate a latest Pleistocene age for youngest movement (~11-15 ka).  Age of Faulted Deposits: Latest Pleistocene (less than15 ka)</gsmlp:description>
			<gsmlp:faultType>Strike slip fault</gsmlp:faultType>
			<gsmlp:movementType>strike-slip</gsmlp:movementType>
			<gsmlp:deformationStyle>brittle</gsmlp:deformationStyle>
			<gsmlp:displacement>The slip rate is estimated at 0.15-0.3 mm/yr based on 15 m of vertical displacement of Upper Mesa deposits, which are roughly estimated to be 50-100 ka.</gsmlp:displacement>
			<gsmlp:geologicHistory>Late Pleistocene;most recent movement Holocene to post-glacial (less than 15 ka)</gsmlp:geologicHistory>
			<gsmlp:observationMethod>Field mapped</gsmlp:observationMethod>
			<gsmlp:positionalAccuracy>Reliability of Location:  Good</gsmlp:positionalAccuracy>
			<gsmlp:source>Data Sources:  The fault zone was mapped and named by Olmsted and others (1973).  Geophysical studies of an area including the Algodones fault were done by Mattick and others (1973).  The fault zone was mapped in more detail and its late Quaternary behavior was investigated by Woodward-McNeil and Associates (1974).  Data Sources:  The fault zone was mapped and named by Olmsted and others (1973).  Geophysical studies of an area including the Algodones fault were done by Mattick and others (1973).  The fault zone was mapped in more detail and its late Quaternary behavior was investigated by Woodward-McNeil &amp; Associates (1974).</gsmlp:source>
			<gsmlp:faultType_uri>http://resource.geosciml.org/classifier/cgi/faulttype/0002</gsmlp:faultType_uri>
			<gsmlp:movementType_uri>http://resource.geosciml.org/classifier/cgi/faultmovementtype/0010</gsmlp:movementType_uri>
			<gsmlp:deformationStyle_uri>missing</gsmlp:deformationStyle_uri>
			<gsmlp:representativeAge_uri>http://resource.geosciml.org/classifier/ics/ischart/Quaternary</gsmlp:representativeAge_uri>
			<gsmlp:representativeLowerAge_uri>http://resource.geosciml.org/classifier/ics/ischart/UpperPleistocene</gsmlp:representativeLowerAge_uri>
			<gsmlp:representativeUpperAge_uri>http://resource.geosciml.org/classifier/ics/ischart/Holocene</gsmlp:representativeUpperAge_uri>
			<gsmlp:specification_uri>http://resources.usgin.org/uri-gin/azgs/fault/QAF.ContactsAndFaults.1/</gsmlp:specification_uri>
			<gsmlp:metadata_uri>String</gsmlp:metadata_uri>
			<gsmlp:genericSymbolizer>2.13.2</gsmlp:genericSymbolizer>
			<gsmlp:shape>
				<gml:MultiCurve>
					<gml:curveMember>
						<gml:LineString>
							<gml:posList>161124.06190000009 3611543.9673999995 161979.24610000011 3610716.1190000009 162613.00519999955 3610107.3936999999 162831.94510000013 3609817.9815999996 163017.37829999998 3609466.9491000008 163061.50970000029 3609371.4321999997 163311.13790000044 3609057.5342999995 163823.2081000004 3608343.2401999999 163984.78160000034 3608228.2546999995 164160.48070000019 3608065.8939999994 164287.68609999958 3607865.9637000002 164431.69280000031 3607696.7251999993 164553.64470000006 3607575.2255000006 164628.26539999992 3607455.5197000001 164687.87119999994 3607359.9025999997</gml:posList>
						</gml:LineString>
					</gml:curveMember>
				</gml:MultiCurve>
			</gsmlp:shape>
		</gsmlp:ShearDisplacementStructureView>
	</gml:featureMember>
</wfs:FeatureCollection>
